





PERSONAL DATA

Citizenship: Russia

Location: Turkey, prefer remote or relocation

SUMMARY

Computational chemist with 12 years of research experience and PhD in (physical) chemistry. Routinely used Python to build automation tools for benchmarking modern computational chemistry methods/conformer search/ML applications. Worked in multidisciplinary teams in close contact with experimental researchers. HPC user.

SKILLS

- Experienced user of modern computational software (ORCA, GAMESS (US), Gaussian, LAMMPS)
- Excellent programming skills (Python, Matlab, C++, bash)
- Proficiency with infrastructure (Linux, Git, Docker, PyCharm, SQL)
- Experience with ML/DL and scientific libraries (TensorFlow, Keras, RDKit, Pandas, NumPy, NLopt, matplotlib)
- · Other software: ChemCraft, Origin

WORK EXPERIENCE

2010 - 2022 Researcher

Chemistry Department, Lomonosov Moscow State University

- Quantum-chemical calculation of short-lived species (PES, spectral parameters, degradation path etc.) using DFT, CASSCF, DLPNO-CCSD etc
- Scientific literature analysis and scientific paper writing (co-authored 34 papers including 8 papers as a first or a sole author)
- Deep learning (TensorFlow, Keras) of material properties based on quantum-chemical data (automated generation using RDKit and ORCA): ongoing project, to be published soon
- Processing, analysis, and visualization of experimental and simulated data, including the fitting of spectral and kinetic data using in-lab or self-written software
- EPR experiments using high-vacuum and high-pressure (under supercritical conditions) equipment

2010 — 2021 (part-time job) Data analyst

Azotecon-plus, Moscow

- Preparation of monthly statistics on the Russian fertilizer market
- Automation of data parsing (from the web, Excel, pdf) and market report assembly using Python

EDUCATION

2004 — 2010 Specialist's degree Lomonosov Moscow State University, Moscow

Chemistry

2010 — 2013 PhD Lomonosov Moscow State University, Moscow

Chemistry

ADDITIONAL EDUCATION

Deep Learning Specialization, Coursera 08/2021

LANGUAGES

English: Professional working proficiency German: Limited working proficiency Italian: Elementary proficiency

Turkish: Elementary proficiency

Russian: Native